A Guide to the Charles Eliot Norton Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8381-a
Charles Eliot Norton Collection 1851
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8381-a
32 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [ 1968 Apr 8 ] 1968 Oct 11
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Charles Eliot Norton to J. S. Clark, 1867 May 27; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions "Revival Literature," "Dictionary of the Bible," by Smith and Harper's "Bible Cyclopaedia."]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to unknown, 1878 Apr 16; ALS, 2 p.
    [Confirms the receipt of $10 for one copy of the reproduction of Turner's etchings; reports on John Ruskin's health.]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to Luigi Palma di Cesnola, 1883 Feb 11; ALS, 4 p.
    [Refers to "drawings" which should be shown at the conveniece of General di Cesnola; suggests Professor Ware's assistance; mentions Mr. Dodge.]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to James R. Osgood, 1884 Apr 7; ALS, 3 p.
    [Suggests the printing of 2000 copies of
    Reminiscences
    to be published in the United States; opposes a publication in England. ]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to Henry (?) Phillips, Jr., 1885 Sep 21; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for a small volume of "Volk Songs" which (?) Phillips has translated into English.]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to James Bradstreet Greenough, 1886 May 10; ALS, 4 p.
    [Asks him to serve as chairman of a Committee on Membership of the Archaeological Institute of America; suggests Thomas Wentworth Higginson and Cardiner M. Lane as the two other members.]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to Bliss Carman, 1891 Aug 16; ALS, 3 p.
    [States that he does not intend, now or later, to write about James Russell Lowell for any journal of public print; suggests that people who have been less close to Lowell should write about him; compliments Carman on his poems.]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to Francis Henry Underwood, 1892 Jan 20; ALS, 4 p.
    [Discusses a paper on James Russell Lowell by Underwood which appeared in the
    Contemporary
    says he would like to read Underwood's "Reminiscences" [
    Quabbin, The Story of A Small Town
    ]; tells of his plan to publish a selection of Lowell's letters with his own "slender narrative" to serve as a biography; mentions poem, "
    Carter's Goat
    . "]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to Mrs. Francis James Lippitt, 1894 Jan 12; ALS, 4 p.
    [Thanks her for the loan of a [Lowell] letter; refers to a notice in the
    Nation
    dealing with Lowell's love-letters, claiming that they have been handed about a large circle of friends; hopes that she can shed light on the matter and is sure that Lowell himself burned the letters, not [Mabel Lowell] Burnett. ]
  - Charles Eliot Norton to Mr. Kimball, 1894 Jan 17; ALS, 2 p.
    [Asks him to visit at a later date unless he has to have his question answered at once.]